Diego Grados

As a bioscience engineer and applied statistician, my work is centered on solving sustainable development challenges in agriculture. I use interdisciplinary approaches focusing on the fundamental and practical aspects of soil-plant-atmosphere interactions, agroecosystem analysis and remote sensing. With extensive involvement in international research projects alongside multidisciplinary partners, I have honed my teamwork and communication skills. I am proficient in programming languages for data-processing applications and process-based modelling. Additionally, I am enthusiastic about creating integrated assessments that utilize data science to translate information into knowledge.

Personal Data

Emaildiegogradosb@agro.au.dkResearchIDGYR-1584-2022Webhttps://diegogradosb.github.ioORCID0000-0001-5548-3204

Relevant Experience

SEP 2020 -PRESENT Postdoctoral Researcher - AARHUS UNIVERSITY, Aarhus - Denmark

Climate and Water - Agroecology Department - Faculty of Technical Sciences

- Mitigation strategies for greenhouse gas emissions (field experiments, data-driven applications, process-based models).
- International collaboration projects: PROENV, MACSUR SciPol, ZERO, KlimaGødning.
- Dissemination of results in seminars, workshops, peer-reviewed journals and international conferences.
- Supervision of MSc and PhD thesis students.

Reference: Prof. Dr. Diego ABALOS, Prof. Dr. Jørgen Eivind OLESEN

Nov 2021 -DEC 2021 **Visiting Researcher** - Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Garmisch-Partenkirchen - Germany Institute of Meteorology and Climate Research, Atmospheric Environmental Research

- Collaboration on using terrestrial ecosystem model LandscapeDNDC to simulate greenhouse gas emissions and yield at the regional and point source level.

Reference: Dr. Edwin HAAS, Dr. Clemens SCHEER

JAN 2020 -

Researcher - KU LEUVEN, Leuven - Belgium

MAR 2020

Mechatronics, Biostatistics and Sensors - Biosystems Department - Faculty of Bioscience Engineering

APR 2016 -

DEC 2019

- Developing multi-target and system modeling methodologies for the agroecosystems' sustainability assessment.
- Dissemination of results in seminars, workshops, peer-reviewed journals and international conferences.
- Supervision of BSc and MSc thesis students in Peru (UNALM and UNCP) and Belgium (KU Leuven).

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eddie SCHREVENS

PhD Researcher

Nov 2014 -Apr 2019 Research Assistant - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Lima - Peru

Strengthening of Smallholder Horticultural Systems Subproject
- Co-leading the study of soil-plant-atmosphere interactions in the Peruvian Coastal Desert.

- Installation of soil, meteorological and irrigation equipment.
- Design, installation and analysis of agricultural experiments under drip irrigation systems.

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Prof. Dr. Guido Wyseure, Prof. Dr. Jan Diels

SEP 2013 -DEC 2018 Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin - Peru Sustainable Agriculture in the Central Peruvian Andes Subproject

- Lead the design, installation and evaluation of agricultural experiments under rainfed conditions.
- Consolidation of rational databases, development of soil-plant-atmosphere models and statistical techniques.
- Analysis of agroecosystems using participatory approaches along with biophysical and biochemical assessments.

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Prof. Dr. Sady García

FEB 2013 -APR 2019 Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin | Lima - Peru

Drone Technology in Agriculture Subproject

- Lead the feasibility study for uses of drone technology in agroecosystems.
- In charge of drone flights in Peruvian's Andes and Arid regions. Implementation of photogrammetric and GIS databases.
- Development of mathematical and statistical workflows for land use classification and field experiments' assessment.

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Sr. R&D Dries RAYMAEKERS

JAN 2012 -DEC 2018 Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin - Peru

Watersheds Management Subproject

- $\hbox{-} \ Lead the study of soil-plant-atmosphere interactions and hydrology in the Peruvian Central Andes. \\$
- Installation of soil, climatological and hydrometric equipment.
- Implementation of databases, application of hydrological models and assessment of rainfall-runoff relations.

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eduardo Chávarri, Prof. Dr. Guido Wyseure

Education

APR 2016 - PhD in Bioscience Engineering, Mechatronics, Biostatistics and Sensors - KU Leuven, Belgium Thesis Title: "Multi-target methodologies for the improvement of agricultural systems research - Study cases at system and field level". | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens

JAN 2007 - **BSc in Agricultural Engineering**, *Hydrology* - Agrarian National University La Molina , Peru

DEC 2011

Honor Thesis Title: "Analysis of flood peaks in small Andean watersheds, Junin Department,

Peru (2011-2012 Period)". | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Eduardo Chávarri

Relevant Publications

- Grados, D., Butterbach-Bahl, K., Chen, J., Van Groenigen, K. J., Olesen, J., Van Groenigen, J. W., Abalos, D., 2022. Synthesizing the evidence of nitrous oxide mitigation practices in agroecosystems. *Environmental Research Letters*. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ac9b50.
- 2. **Grados, D.**, Reynafarje, X., Schrevens, E., 2020. A methodological approach to assess canopy NDVI–based tomato dynamics under irrigation treatments. *Journal of Agricultural Water Management*, 240, 106208. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.agwat.2020.106208.
- 3. **Grados, D.,** García, S., Schrevens, E., 2020. Assessing the potato yield gap in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Journal of Agricultural Systems*, 181, 102817. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.agsy.2020.102817.
- 4. **Grados, D.,** Schrevens, E., 2019. Multidimensional analysis of environmental impacts from potato agricultural production in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Science of The Total Environment*, 663, 927–934. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.01.414.

Relevant Conference Proceedings [PEER-REVIEWED]

- Grados, D., García, S., Schrevens, E., Nitrogen and water use efficiency under rain-fed potato agriculture: An experimental study. *Acta Horticulturae* (1253, 243–252). *International Symposium on Water and Nutrient Relations and Management of Horticultural Crops*, Istanbul, Turkey, 12-16 Aug 2018. http://doi.org/10.17660/actahortic.2019.1253.33.
- Grados, D., Vetters, E., Heuts, R., Schrevens, E., A model based technical sustainability analysis of potato production systems in the Mantaro Valley, Central Highlands, Peru. *Acta Horticulturae (1154, 155-152)*. Symposium on Applications of Modelling as an Innovative Technology in the Horticultural Supply Chain, Wageningen, The Netherlands, 11-14 Oct 2015. http://doi.org/10.17660/actahortic. 2017.1154.20.
- Grados, D., Vera, J., Schrevens, E., Corn-faba bean associations in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Acta Horticulturae* (1128, 79-88). *International Symposium on Horticulture in Developing Countries and World Food Production*, Brisbane, Australia, 19-22 Aug 2014. http://doi.org/10.17660/actahortic.2016. 1128.11.

Teaching Experience

- FA 2021 Carbon Cycling and Climate Change Master in Agrobiology, Aarhus University
 - Teacher Assistant: I lectured on soil nitrogen cycling and nitrous oxide emissions. I guided students during the discussion and practical sessions to assess agroecosystems. I supported them on the development of their research papers. [10-20 students]
- FA 2017 Applied Multivariate Statistical Analysis Master in Bioscience Engineering, KU Leuven
 - Teacher Assistant: I taught students how to analyze their databases using statistical software by leading R-tutorials. I was responsible for the practical sessions on data wrangling and visualization, matrix algebra, R-programming and advanced multivariate techniques. [80 students]
- FA 2019 Biological Production Systems Bachelor in Bioscience Engineering, **KU Leuven**Teacher Assistant: I guided students during discussions and practical sessions to assess agroecosystems.

 I taught them the essentials of process-based mathematical modelling and supported them on the development of their research papers. [25 students]
- SP 2016 Ecosystems Modelling Master in Bioscience Engineering, **KU Leuven**Teacher Assistant: I taught students how to develop and utilize ecosystems models at diverse scales by leading R-tutorials. I guided the practical sessions on mathematical and statistical concepts, data wrangling and visualization, R-programming. I taught them the fundamental topics on process-based modelling of ecosystems: identification, implementation, calibration and validation. [10 students]

Fellowships

- 2022 **Aarhus University** Travel Grant [400€]
- 2021 **iCLIMATE** Research Grant [3 600€]
- .020 **FONDECYT-CONCYTEC** Research Grant [5 500€]
- 2016 2019 VLIR/UOS-UNALM PhD Fellowship [82 000€]
- 2013 | 2014 | 2015 VLIR/UOS-UNALM International Scholar Fellowships [67 000€]

Ad-Hoc Reviewer

Agronomy for Sustainable Development, Agricultural Systems, European Journal of Agronomy, Geoderma, Journal of Cleaner Production, Plant and Soil, Soil Use and Management.

Languages

English: Full professional proficiency

French: Limited working proficiency

Spanish: Native/Bilingual

Technical Skills

Programming R, Python, MATLAB
Markup Markdown, LaTeX

Other RStudio, Spyder, Office, QGIS, ArcGIS, Git/GitHub, HTML/CSS, Make, HPC